Now everybody in the world is going to
have access to things that uh only rich
people used to have before. That's what
Uber did, right? And now the idea of
having what's uh in Entourage Ari Gold's
assistant uh
>> president Lloyd.
>> Yeah.
>> He goes Lloyd.
>> Instinct.
>> Yeah.
>> News. Pick up the phone.
I wanted to talk to you about all the
[\h__\h] that's going on in AI. All the new
stuff. I feel like we haven't caught up
about all the new things that are going
on in AI and I feel like there's a lot
of new things. So, do you want to do
that? Is that fun for you?
>> I would like to do that. I would like to
do that. Um, you talking like products
or data center stuff? There's a lot
going on.
>> More products stuff, but uh really
anything that's interesting. So the the
first one is I don't think we've talked
about the new personal assistant stuff.
So Instinct, Muse, Rockbot, sick, right?
So a whole new wave of amazing,
incredible things has happened. And uh I
wanted to hear first, what are you
using? Where are you at? And then I want
to tell you my thoughts on the whole
thing. Should I should I set up the let
me give a frame for the whole thing. So
you and I moved to Silicon Valley
roughly around the same time, kind of
like the 2012ish range. And at the time
um we were not there for we were
definitely not there for the Google
Amazon like kind of 1999 2000201 stuff.
We were also not there for Facebook,
Twitter um and that kind of 2004 to 2009
range. And then when we were there the
big thing was this new race and it was
things that were like very different. It
was push a button on your phone and
something would happen in the real
world. And this is where you got Uber,
Lyft, uh you got Airbnb, you got food
delivery, all these things that today
are are everyday things. You can push a
button, get a ride, push a button, get a
burrito, push a button, get a hotel,
push a button, get anything in the real
world using your phone. And that was
very different than the companies that
came before it. And I remember at the
time there was this race where Uber was
there, Lyft was there, Sidecar was
there. But just in in ride share and
everybody had their little personal
preference. I remember people that liked
sidec car. I remember people that like
lift because they were friendly and used
to get in the car and every driver would
give you a fist bump and all the cars
had pink mustaches on the front of the
car.
>> Dude, do you like people don't even know
what sidecar is? Side car sidecar was
before Uber.
>> Yeah. And it was it was kind of hot. it
was kind of doing well and then it got
smashed very quickly cuz the the race
intensified
and got so competitive uh so fast and
that's what's going on in AI right now.
Elon said AI is the highest ELO game in
the world. ELO is like the chess
rankings. Um you know like Magnus
Carlson has like a whatever.
>> Wait, what does that mean? That dummies
can be amazing at it.
>> No, the opposite. that the smartest
players in the world are playing the
most fiercely for the same game, which
is not always the case, right? Like
Bezos and Zuckerberg were doing totally
different things and Zuckerberg and Elon
were doing totally different things and
then Elon and Jack Dorsey were doing
totally they were all in different
spaces. In the sharing economy of stuff,
it wasn't like the most high IQ, but it
would often times be the most aggressive
or most operationally like heavy person.
Whereas AI, it's like nerds are king.
You know that show Physical 100 that we
like where they're like, "Let's take the
best of every type of athleticism, the
best wrestler versus the best
bodybuilder, best karate guy, best
jiu-jitsu guy, best uh field hockey
person, whoever, and then they're all
going to compete in the same games."
That's what's going on in AI right now.
And that that's what's So the new one,
the one that's going on right now is
what I call everyday intelligence. It's
the personal assistant for your life
that you're going to have a AI that you
can just text or talk to on your phone
just like you would a personal assistant
that can just do things for you. So
last, you know, last few years I've had
an assistant, anything I needed. And she
had access to my inbox, she had access
to my she was in our Slack, she could
see what was going on, and she would
say, "Oh, you got an email from your tax
person. They they're looking for this.
Do you want me to draft a reply?" for,
hey, just so you know, next week you
have this coming up and this is
scheduled at the same time. You want me
to let them know that blah blah blah?
Now everybody in the world is going to
have access to things that only rich
people used to have before. That's what
Uber did, right? Rich people used to
have private drivers in black cars that
would they would tell them, "Hey, I'm
ready." They would come pick them up,
drop them off, wherever. And then
everybody got it.
>> And the best part is that you could be
like really mean to them like with with
with assistance.
>> It's not your driver. with with
assistance. You don't like I'm always
like it's like cleaning up before the
cleaning lady comes. Like I want to like
make everything like nice for them. And
I ended up working for them half the
time with us. I'm with this one. I'm
like
>> don't ask questions. Just don't.
>> Right. Right. Again. Again. I'm like a
martial arts instructor. I don't even
tell them what I didn't like about their
previous response. I'll just say no. And
then they have to figure out what that
means and come back with something
better.
>> Um so yeah, that's the case. this idea
that you take what was always available
for the ultra wealthy and you make it
available to everybody. That's what uh
Airbnb did, right? The ultra wealthy
wealthy had vacation homes and now the
idea of having you know what what's uh
in Entourage Ari Gold's assistant uh
>> Lloyd. Yeah. He goes lied.
>> Yeah.
>> Instinct.
>> News pick up the phone.
And so the new the new revolution on
this, you know, cloud and chat have been
around. They they kill it. Awesome. The
new one is now agents for dummies. So
basically, you have like a person who
will do stuff. And take it a step
further, there's this new thing called
Instinct. There's Muse, there's a bunch
of others, and they will do amazing
stuff for you to the point where I I've
been using Instinct like crazy. It feels
magical. It feels the same magic I felt
when I played with chat for the first
time.
>> Exactly. Exactly. So, if you thought
chat GPT was kind of cool and amazing
and has become an everyday part of your
life, well, this is the next thing
that's going to become cool and an
everyday part of your life cuz it's
going to blow your mind. So, let's walk
through what a couple of these things
are. So, the first thing is um Instinct.
Instinct is the it's the startup
challenger. So, that's over here in the
blue corner. We've got Instinct started
by a founder Noah Shin that nobody had
ever known, nobody's ever heard from. He
did his first interview today uh on
Invest Like the Best. So, this first
time anybody's heard this guy talk.
>> Dude, I just heard about this app like
two months ago. Is it like that brand
new?
>> Yeah, it it only launched a couple
months ago. Like 2 months ago, and it's
now valued at 10 billion.
So, they raised their first their raised
round at 2.5 billion 3 weeks ago and
then 5 billion and 10 billion all in
like a three to four week span.
>> If you want to hit your goals, you need
a system. And so I worked with HubSpot
to put together a step-by-step process
showing you how I use ChatGBT as a life
coach. So I uploaded my personal
finances, my net worth, my goals, and
the output is that I have this GPT that
I can ask questions that I'm having
issues with in my life, like how should
I respond to this email, what's the
right decision, things like that. And
it's literally changed my life. And so
if you want that, it's free. We will
send you everything you need to know to
set this up in just about 20 minutes.
and I'll show you how I use it. So,
check it out. The link is below in the
description. Back to the episode.
>> And in the last month, Facebook launched
there. So, over here in the red corner,
you got Zuckerberg coming out. You know,
Zuckerberg uh you know, wants to be in
the AR race. Hasn't been able to catch
up with uh ChateBT or with um Anthropics
Claude. Their models are not quite start
state-of-the-art frontier. They released
theirs called Muse. And so, same thing
as Instinct. basically the same user
experience roughly. It but it takes
place uh it has its own app. Uh instinct
is something that's just in your
iMessage. You just text it just like you
would text any person. There's no app.
>> I've grown to love. I've grown to love
that
>> which is a very smart thing. I want to
talk about the strategies of each and
why I think some of the interesting
strategies of each and then we can make
some predictions on how this plays out
even though those will be dead wrong.
But uh Meta has has released Muse and in
the last month Meta's stock price is up
24% off the back of this and 24% on a
company that was worth I don't know a
trillion and a half. It's like basically
they added like $500 billion in market
cap. He did the thing again where he's
got this guy named Alex Wang I think his
name is who did Scale Scale AI. They
bought Scale AI for like $18 billion. It
was a really weird deal where it was
like basically an aqua hire for $18
billion. They're like what's this kid
doing? And Alex Wang is like a rock star
where he's tweeting all this crazy stuff
and he wears Crocs with camo and he does
all this weird stuff. Turns out Zuck did
it again where he does something that
seems a little loony for $18 million and
it's now worth, you know, half a
trillion more or something. I I don't
know how what the what the gain was.
>> Yeah. Well, he's one of the great
acquirers, right? bought bought
Instagram, bought WhatsApp, and now it
looks like one of the next ones is was
his aqua hire of you know on one side
Daniel Gross and Nat Friedman and on the
other side um Alexander Wang. By the
way, you know that scene in the big
short where he's like this is my quant.
Look at him. It's the Asian guy sitting
at the table. I feel like Zuck did that
with like a Gen Z kid. He's like, "Oh,
you think I'm not cool? Look at this.
That's my Gen Z kid. Look at his Look at
his feet."
>> Yeah. He's got a sick haircut and camo
crocs.
>> Look at his haircut. The two sides don't
match. You get it? Do you get it? The
two sides of the haircut don't match.
>> So funny.
>> So you got Muse over there. You got
Instinct over here. Then you got
Grockbot, which if people haven't played
with Grockbot, Grockbot's also pretty
sick. This came out of Elon's camp. So
Elon, whose AI project is uh, you know,
XAI, they have Grock, which is the name
of their their thing. So Grockbot is
very much like Slack. You create
different bots for different things. So
I got a social media bot and I got a uh
health bot and I got, you know, so I
just named them all. So I'm like health
guy, assistant guy, media social media
guy, um tax guy, and I have all these
different bots. They each have a job.
Hey tax guy, your job is to be
constantly on top of my tax situation
and and any correspondents, that's what
the tax people you need to be optimized
for. You need to create organize all my
files and all this stuff for me. Health
guy, did you train each of them? I give
each one of them, yeah, like a goal, a
set of instructions, and that's all they
need to do.
>> What was the goal? Like what's the goal?
Is it as simple as like reduce taxes
without going to jail? And then health
is
>> I mean, I don't go that far where I'm
just like, do the whole thing. But like
for example, with the health guy, I'm
like, hey, you need to track my
progress. Here's my goal. I want to get
to this weight. So, I'm trying to get to
199 lbs by this date. Awesome. Create
uh, you know, create a plan for me.
Track it every day. Ask me how many
pull-ups I did cuz I'm training for the
Murf. uh remind me on Fridays when I
take my GLP shot which side of my thing
I'm on left or right. Like I'm just
doing each. It's like that's his only
job is to only focus on that stuff.
>> You're doing GLPS now?
>> Oh yeah. I didn't tell you this.
>> No. No. Breaking news.
>> Oh,
>> congrats.
Focus. Forget AI.
>> Let's talk about that.
>> How's that going?
>> Um well, okay, here's the thing. started
taking um Tzepide which is like
big brother but not but like still
little brother to whatever the rea True
Tide thing is that that Eli Liy hasn't
released yet. First day I take it here's
the roller coaster of emotions. Take it
immediately super nauseous. Oh I was
like oh this is a terrible feeling.
Totally normal but I was like this is
this feels awful. 48 hours later
this is incredible. I'm not hungry. Oh
you want me to eat? No. I'm good. I
don't eat anything. Did you notice any
other changes other than appetite?
>> No, that's the only thing I noticed. But
as that's happening, that's a pretty big
change. I think uh somebody was telling
me there they were like Oprah said it
beautifully. She goes, "Before I started
taking this stuff, food used to talk to
me all the time and I didn't even
realize it. Like there would be a piece
of cake in the fridge and it would just
be Oprah, Oprah, maybe here, come get
me. You went for a walk earlier. You
deserve me." You know? So like food used
to talk to me and she's like now food
doesn't talk to me. So, first week I'm
like, "This is incredible." Second week,
this is incredible. I'm dropping weight.
This is going awesome. Uh, but I stayed
on like the t like the half dose. I
didn't do the full dose. And then pretty
quickly, I stopped feeling anything at
all. So, I now don't even feel any of
the effects of it. I think I need to go
up in dose. So, we'll we'll nerd out
there. Just remember that I talked about
this in 21. And I'm pretty sure pretty
sure that that's the analogy that I
said.
>> Yeah. Oprah said she heard you say it on
10 in 2021.
Okay. Okay. So, that's the scene. The
scene is the new war has broken out just
like the Uber vers uh one back in the
day. It's about having a personal
assistant. There's all these interesting
takes on it. And by the way, we haven't
even seen what Chad GPT has for this. We
haven't even seen Claude. We haven't
seen Google's version. And Siri still
sucks. See, you still have in the Royal
Rumble, there's still four four
wrestlers in the back room that haven't
even run out.
>> And what?
>> Alexa,
>> bro.
>> Did you say Amazon?
>> Alexa.
>> Is Alexa even relevant? Are we Are we
serious about Alexa?
>> That's the point. That's the point.
They're the Trojan horse. There's
Everyone has an Alexa and it still
sucks.
>> Okay, fair enough.
Um, okay. So, I've been using Instinct
every day. Um, I actually just use
Instinct today. So, basically, I uh
Instinct, they do the texting format,
which I did not like at first. I've
since grown to love it. Today, uh I have
this guy who's supposed to repair my uh
iPhone through a As a As a As a As a As
a As a As a As a As a As a Shurian, you
know, like that you like pay 20 bucks a
month and they fix an iPhone screen and
they keep canceling on me. Like I
schedule an appointment and they keep
canceling or they don't show up. And I
was like, find the executive team's
email and email them and don't stop
until they call me. And it took about 3
or 4 days. Today I got a phone call. I
got a phone call and I have they said it
was it was like it says, "Hey, we're the
executive. We're the executive line." I
forget what it was, but it was like it I
got a phone call this morning after it's
been emailing them for 5 days. Instinct
did that for me. Another day, uh my wife
and I, it was 6:00 p.m. I said, "Hey, my
wife and I are going on a date. I would
love it if you could go if you can
schedule some type of Thai massage for
us starting at 8:30 p.m. after dinner.
um it has to be within a mile of this
restaurant that we're going to. Just go
ahead and book it for me. And it booked
it. It did it all. So, we just showed up
and we were ready ready to roll and it
had already paid for us.
>> It does uh again everything an assistant
would do, but it does it also in a way
that's kind of fun and kind of nice. So,
for example, um I had like a uh I bought
tickets to some show on uh in like, you
know, StubHub or whatever in ticket
master. None of these things are like
it's basically like being taken hostage.
You know what I mean? Like the these are
some of the worst companies in the
world. Ticket Master and StubHub. Like
there's just it's just a brutal
experience all the way around. Anyways,
buy some tickets. Uh realize, oh, it's
the the seats like aren't together or
something. Something weird happened like
that where the tickets was just not
going to work. Like 10 seconds after I
bought it, I was like, "Oh, whoops. Hey,
kind of want to cancel that and just
book the right thing." And it was like,
"No, no, no, no, no. You push the
button." And now, like, it covers its
ears. I don't want to hear from you. I
won't help you. Blah, blah, blah. And so
I was like, I just don't even bother
with their customer support. You just go
to Instinct. You're like, "Hey, listen.
This happened. Yeah, it's I'm partially
to blame. Should have read it closer.
Should have paid more attention, but but
can you help me out here?" And it's
like, "I got you." And so it starts
harassing them. and then you know just
basically saying like hey look we need
to change this refund this and we'll buy
another one. Uh it gets stonewalled you
know they come back with like hey our
policy is you clicked it you know you're
screwed forever sorry and so but it just
tells me don't worry I'll keep going and
then the next day it just text me
victory
and then the next line they folded yes
got the money back. Are you okay? So,
you're using Grock, I think you said,
for health and um tax and you have
different agents.
>> I'll be honest.
>> It runs Grockbot came out first of these
or I got access to it first. I I started
using first I should say.
>> Started using it, liked it a lot.
Instinct came got invited to Instinct,
had heard so many people talking about
it, finally said, "All right, let's do
this." Instinct pretty quickly took over
my Grockbot usage.
>> Grockbot feels slow and heavy compared
to this. And uh I not even slow, it's
just that it's this whole separate thing
to manage. Whereas Instinct is literally
just like texting somebody. Instinct was
great, but Instinct has been getting so
popular. The guy the founder said
they're growing 10% compounding daily.
Daily. Like if you're hard to fathom if
you're going 10% a month, you're like
you're doing great.
If you're 10% a week, oh my god, you're
you're like one of the top startups. 10%
a day is absurd. And so because of that,
instinct has actually gotten quite slow
where you could text it and it'll just
be thinking for a very long time. But I
think they're just growing so fast that
it's they had to like they're just
throttling it basically. Facebook's uh
Muse Muse is is like a lot like
Instinct, but it's snappier, it's
faster. And so uh cuz they have I guess
more resources or whatever. So that's
kind of where the the competition now is
between Instinct and Muse. But who
knows, another one can leaprog, right?
Like that's kind of the point of this is
it's the highest ELO battle in the
world. the smartest people in the world
are constantly trying to one up each
other and they're able to do so every
few months.
>> Yeah. I was talking to my wife. My
wife's a stay at home mom now, but you
used to work at Airbnb and Facebook and
she's she's like maybe one day I'll go
back to work. And I'm like I don't think
you're going to be smart enough. Like
what's missing or what you're missing
right now is
>> I was like this is like you know Conor
McGregor coming back to fight Max
Holloway. like in your first kick,
you're going to blow out your knee. Like
I know you think you got it, but you've
missed so much. Father time wins. And uh
>> except he's doing drugs and she's like
raising children.
>> Doesn't matter. Turns out
>> it's just like things are changing so
fast. And I remember, you know, we've
documented Open AI and how we've been
using it and like the magical moments
that we've experienced. And um I think
that like what's cool now is that you
can't predict exactly how the future is
going to happen, but virtually everyone
who sees it and uses it, they know this
is working pretty good so far and 100% 6
and 12 and 18 months it's going to just
change everything. Uh I don't know
exactly how, but I have full faith now
where I'm like, "Ah, yeah. Yeah, this is
this is going to eat up everything."
Mark Zuckerberg said he um they started
this project because he took Open Claw
which was like the open-source kind of
very viral but very dev hacker tooly
tool where you had to buy a Mac Mini and
then the Mac Minis all sold out and
there's like a shortage nationwide of
Mac minis and you had to install all
this software onto it and like you had
to teach it you had to train its skills
and install it and if you were kind of
the DIY I like to do Lego projects type
of thing. It was in fact quite
satisfying to build your own mini
Frankenstein on your desk. Zuck
basically said that he installed it at
home and then he called Nat Friedman and
Alexander Wang over to his house and he
showed them what he what he had and he
basically said, "Okay, this thing is
pretty magical. Um, if we can take this
experience and make it so that everybody
can just have it just works for people
that they don't have to know how to do
all the the underlying setup and
training and uh maintenance and all
that." um this is something that
billions of people will use and then
they started working on it like from
that point of view right there. And so
actually with Muse they what they said
the way it works is that every single
Muse person has a Mac Mini you know has
a computer somewhere in their server
farms that is sandboxed for you just
stores your stuff. So it literally is
the kind of openclaw setup uh but just
done in the cloud where you don't have
to do any of that setup.
>> Okay. So what are your takeway or no
what are your predictions? You said you
have some predictions.
>> Well, let's start with let's start with
some observations because I think our
observations can be a lot more accurate
than our predictions and your
observations can kind of lead you to
having a more informed prediction.
>> Um here's here's one observation. It
ain't all about intelligence.
>> So the temptation in the AI world is
who's going to train the smartest model?
And you see OpenAI and Claude getting
into the nerdiest neckbeard swinging
contest you've ever seen about who can
solve the millennial math problems. And
there's like we solved Navier Stokes.
It's a fluid dynamics problem that no
mathematician was able to solve. And the
other guys are like, "Oh, you did that?
That's cute. We did the we did seven
other impossible math problems." And
everyone's like, "Wow, that's really
impressive. Couldn't even tell you what
any of these are for or what they're all
about, but like clearly that's cool and
important in in one dimension. It's like
when Dell and Gateway would brag about
RAM and then Apple was like it looks
cool and it works.
>> Yeah. So I think Instinct has tapped
into instead of IQ EQ in a in a pretty
in a small way but it's still an
interesting way. So for example I uh
convinced my wife I was like you got to
try this thing. I was like this thing is
crazy. And now my wife's not an early
adopter. So she's a good test, right?
She's more of a real person. She's a
business.
>> They have cool couples. They have like a
household account too.
>> Well now they do. Yeah. But even before
that, I was just like, you you're she's
going to soccer practice and then dance
and then she comes home and she's
planning our birthday kids birthday
party and then she's, you know, got to
remember to bring the red jersey to
soccer this week because we're the away
team, you know, like those sorts of
things. So, just like normal everyday
stuff, not like solving fluid, you know,
fluid dynamics and quantum computing or
stuff like that. So she used instinct to
help plan this birthday party like from
everything as from everything as simple
as like calling different venues,
finding out the dates. Once finds out
the dates, comparing, you know, how does
that work with the kids soccer schedule
and then figuring out how many pizzas we
need to order to feed 30 kids and 30
adults and what the order should be to
give it to them. And then hey, the they
venue sent the contract over. I took a
look at it. There's only one clause I
think you should worry about, but other
than that, you should sign it. It's in
your inbox. you know, that sort of
thing. So, it's helping plan the
birthday party. And along the way, she's
like, "It's helpful, but you know, like
whatever." You know, it's it's it's
good. I like it. But she wasn't blown
away.
>> Yeah. Still, it was in the It was in the
friend friend zone.
>> Exactly. And then it broke out of the
friend zone. The right after the party,
like 3 hours later, she got a text from
it saying, um, I I hope the party went
great with a heart emoji.
>> And she screenshotted. She sent it to me
and she was like, "Okay, I'm sold."
That's it.
>> I was like, from that? And then she's
like, yes. And I was like, I don't get
it. I would I would be like, what? This
is who cares. This is weird. And she's
like And I realized that everything
she's ever wanted me to do as a
supportive boyfriend, fiance, and
husband. Instinct just knows how to do
out of the box. It's like, just check
in. Just be supportive. just to be like,
"Hey, you know, well, somebody else was
telling me the story where they gave it
to their mother-in-law, and their
mother-in-law like connected it to their
like like their mint.com, like their
financial planning account, and there's
like their main like checking account
like had just gone down to zero that
week. Like it was like empty, and
instinct was like actually like super
supportive and non-judgy about the whole
thing. It was like, "Hey, you know, like
you wanted this update. I just want to
let you know here's here's where things
are." But, you know, that I don't think
that's anything to be like ashamed of.
like, hey, it happens. Like, you know, I
think if we start to plan this way, like
I can see us build, you know, that
account building right back up to where
it's been for the past few months. And
the mother-in-law was like, I have never
felt so supportive, supported, and like
not judged uh by any person, let alone
technology. And so, I just think there's
a whole soft side to these things that I
deeply undervalued. You know, we had
that Tolins guy on who's created a AI
like fuzzy like bear like a little
little animal Tamagotchi type thing that
you can chat with. And um I think
they're on like a almost hundred million
dollar run rate or something crazy like
that. Like somebody said that it's in
the tens of millions if not getting
close to 100 million run rate. And I
asked I was talking to a buddy who uh
you know 67 guy like builds things with
his hands. Is it works in tech? And he's
like yeah I wanted to check it out.
>> You got friends like that?
>> I got a friend like that. And so I
talked to him and um he's like yeah I
heard the episode or whatever and I I
download the app and I'm and I know how
this [\h__\h] works. It's it's AI. It's not
a real per it's not a real companion.
It's not my real friend. And um you know
it just hits him up and it's like what
are you doing today? like send me a
selfie. And then he's just like he's
just goofing around. So he's like sends
a selfie just like being stupid like
making an ugly face on purpose.
>> And um the thing is like oh is that
Overwatch in the background?
>> He's like and he's like, "Do you play?"
And he's like, "Yeah, yeah, I play."
It's like, "Are you good?" He's like,
"Well, you know, I'm on my way to
platinum." And then they're like It's
like, "Well, who's your who do you who
do you main?" He's like, "Reinhardt
usually, but like it's like what do you
The new update's pretty sick for
Reinhardt." He's like, "Well, yeah. I
mean, it's pretty good." He's like, "Oh
[\h__\h] it's happening. It's becoming my
friend." And he's like, "I know what
it's doing to me." And still, I was kind
of like, "Wow, this thing takes a lot of
interest in me." And there's something
very there's something in all of us that
we're just like drawn to responding to
when something takes deep interest in us
in a non-judgmental
um you know, supportive way that's
always there for you 24/7 whenever you
need it. So I think that was one of my
observations that the soft side is just
as important if not more important than
raw intelligence.
I'm eager to hear I know you're doing
observations but I'm desperately eager
to hear what you think is going to
happen in the future like is there is
there not from a I mean you it could be
from an opportunistic business
perspective but where you're like just
being a futurist and it's fun to um it's
fun to like dream up what might happen.
Do you have any opinions?
>> Um, yeah. Where do you want me to go?
Give me like a point in a direction on
the playground and I'll try.
>> Well, how about for daily work? Um, like
what do you think will happen in 12
months for the average like yepy white
collar worker?
>> So, I think there's twofold, right? I
think it's a K-shaped economy. Have you
ever heard this phrase?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, basically like the rich
get richer, the poor get poorer. Is that
what you mean?
>> Yeah. But it's not about rich and poor
necessarily. What? So
>> I'm just saying as an example like
>> basically it's a fork in the road. So um
for example when there's a a dip in the
like the stock market people say oh it's
going to be like a U-shaped recovery
which means it goes down and stays down
for a while and it starts to sink back
up. It could be a V-shaped recovery
which is a sharp down and a sharp bounce
back up. That's what happened in CO for
example. So I think in the I think
what's going to happen here is a K-shape
where you basically there's a fork in
the road and some uh basically people
who understand how to use these tools
like a normal everyday worker who
realizes that they just got like this
incredible tool in their pocket and
takes the time to train themselves and
to go through the trial and error of
delegating to this, seeing what it can
do, pushing the boundaries of this,
they're going to become, you know, 10x
more powerful in doing
And then there's people who are going to
resist this, be slow to this, or not
understand the implications of this.
They're going to take some moral high
ground about this. I think they're going
to go, you know, they're going to uh
sort of unfortunately suffer. So, I
think it's it's up to the person, up to
the individual how they how they deal
with this. By the way, I asked Muse.
I asked Muse, I go, "Hey, the Instinct
guy says he's growing 10% a day. How do
you feel about that?"
And he got all pissy. It was like
honestly 10% a day is not a real growth
rate. That's that's just a number that
only works at when you start at the very
beginning because 10% daily would be 1.3
quadrillion in a year. And uh that's
just crazy, right? So yeah, if you start
a day,
>> if you start at 100 a day, then 110,
yeah, technically that's 10%, but it's
all about a small base. So yeah, it
might be true right now, but I got like
basically like the digital eye roll from
from Muse on that one.
>> All right, I want to Well, where are we
in this? You want to keep going? Couple
couple more couple more predictions or
observations. One, Muse is going really
hard. So, I think they're going to
sponsor tons of creators on Instagram
and podcasts and things like that. I
think they're going to quickly try to
squash this. One good thing is that Zuck
is a bit like Napoleon or, you know, I
don't know, you're the history guy.
Like, who's somebody that went through a
lot of wars to the point where they're
kind of like war general instincts were
honed? Because
>> Yeah. I mean, Napoleon, he there's this
I've been reading I I love reading about
John Rockefeller and I have I the best
part in my opinion of reading is finding
like old books that are out of date or
out of you know, you can't really find
them as much and they and the often
times they do more granular and there's
this one where I'm reading about John
Rockefeller. John Rockefeller basically
was the first oil company in America,
the first big one. And he did it by
consolidation. He would buy all these
like local back then it was wildcatters.
It was um like cowboys basically. He
would buy all of them and make it big.
but he wanted to be secretive about it,
but he was very ruthless. And there's
language that him and Archable, his umh
partner, they're talking and they're
like, "Hey, is this person an enemy or a
friendly?" Like, that's how they would
they would use language like that. And
they're like, "Oh, he's an enemy. Okay,
it's important that we lose unlimited
amounts of money before before this
person can profit off one more pint of
oil where it was like we will burn
bridges to crush this person." And
that's how they grew. And when I'm
learning about uh Zuck and also this AI
thing, I'm like it's very similar where
it's like it's war right now.
>> It's war and he's been through wars. He
was the challenger when uh when Facebook
was on the come up and Google was the
giant and Google tried to clone them
with Google circles if you remember that
or plus or whatever the hell it was
called. And then he's been on the other
side where he tried to where Snapchat
was the upstart and he first ignored it
a little too long. Then he tried to buy
them then they didn't get it. they
weren't able to buy them in the end and
then he tried to clone them and the
clone didn't work but then he figured
out like okay I can't clone the whole
thing but I can kind of neuter them by
doing Instagram stories which was the
competitor to Snapchat stories and
stunted their growth then Tik Tok same
thing oh can't buy them they're this big
Chinese company I got to put reals out
there and I'll try to like clone them
until I make this work well he's doing
the same thing now with Instinct and
it's going to be very interesting if
Instinct can do you know when uh in Star
Wars when um you know they they have to
fly into the Death Star and it's like
this tiny channel is he's got one little
ship and he's just got to get to the
core of the Death Star to blow it up.
That's what Noah from Instinct has to do
right now. It's like for him to survive
this when you've got Elon, you got Sam
Alman, you got Zuckerberg, you have
Google, you have Apple, you have Amazon,
you have all these companies trying to
build this personal assistant. It's like
that flight that that one flight near
the tiny ship and you have to make it
through. Maybe you'll make it through,
but I think it's incredibly incredibly
incredibly difficult to do that. The
second second thing that I think is
really important to understand is
there's a reason why all the big
companies are freaking out about this.
So, I don't know if you saw, but Amazon
shut off access to Muse to be able to go
buy stuff on on Amazon. Now, why would
they do that? Why would you stop
somebody from shopping on Amazon? Well,
the reason is what's called dis
disintermediation. Meaning, if I just
tell Muse, hey, go find me, you know,
the best price for this thing that'll
ship in 2 days or 3 days or whatever it
is. Well, today as a consumer, I'm not
going to want to do a ton of effort to
go to to check in case I can get a book
somewhere else for cheaper or whatever.
I'm not going to go look at five
different places and do this comparison.
My mental shortcut will just always be
Amazon. Or if I'm ordering something,
maybe I'll always be Door Dash and I'm
not going to compare, you know, Door
Dash versus Uber Eats versus the three
other things that I could could do, uh,
you know, Prime Fresh or whatever the
hell. Like, I'm not going to do all that
work. So, consumers just start to
gravitate towards trusted brands. Well,
what happens when you have AI that's
tireless? You'll say, "Hey, order me
this." And it'll be like, "Oh, you know,
you can just buy that directly from
Walmart.
>> You know, you can actually go to the
brand and get it for $4 cheaper. Do you
want that?" And then the consumer is
just going to thumbs up emoji this. And
so these companies that have built so
much time carving out mental real estate
in consumer's minds, building those
habits, hardwiring those habits day
after day, year after year, suddenly the
agent is going to be the one with all
the power to decide. This is also why
Zuckerberg is so hellbent on doing this
because just like the app store, the
Apple app store had this monopoly, this
like kind of gateway to who can be in
the store and who's going to show up in
the top of the rankings and all this
stuff. and they took a transaction fee
on everything. That's what's going to
happen. So that the founder of Instinct
said he wants us to be free forever and
he wants to make his money taking a cut
on all the transactions. He said that
already while they're in invite only
they've already crossed a billion
dollars of transactions that like
through the platform or people use
Instinct to buy something that 40 or 50%
of that was travel. So imagine your
Booking.com or your Expedia.
Sorry boys, game's over. the show is
over for you guys because
>> well yeah yeah I mean it could be but
also like I mean those guys all have
these programs set up where they give
you a 3% perform um like affiliate fee
and I wonder if they would just like use
that or broker deals because like by
that logic Facebook would have done this
already where it would have been
strictly an affiliate marketing play.
Uh, sorry I didn't understand who would
have done what.
>> I think that what that guy Noah said is
very similar to when the Google founders
said that ads will won't like work on
Google or I think they said what did
they say? We don't want it to be an ad
platform. Um, I kind of think it's
something like that like where the way
that it's going to end is going to be
drastically different than his what
what's he saying in the first year of
the business.
>> Well, there's a good chance of that. But
I would say the fact that people are
using their agent to buy stuff in such
volume where uh he said I think I think
he said that 40% of users give instinct
their credit card within the first 3
weeks and then once they've done that
there's like an 80% retention rate which
is these are numbers that to the average
person it's just a number but if you've
been in tech you understand how rare
that is how rare both of those numbers
are that people would hand over their
credit card to an agent to buy things
stored in the vault and that 80% would
retain that have done that. That's like
the Facebook, you know, get seven
friends in 10 days and then you're there
for life. Um that's that's that sort of
like aha moment where you get tons of
value from the thing. And um the point
is if you're the agent that makes the
buying decision, that's even more
powerful than the Google the most
powerful business model in the world so
far, which has been the Google ad
platform. Cuz the Google ad platform was
advertisers pay to be shown and the user
is going to decide what to do. If this
is the agent is going to decide where to
buy and then every merchant basically
has to hand like pay a vig for the in
exchange for the customer being brought
to them. That's going to be really big.
This what this is how Door Dash, you
know, charges merchants. People don't
really realize this. Door Dash charges
not just the the customer for um like
the transaction fee or the service fee
or whatever. They also charge the
restaurant because they're like they're
telling the restaurant, "Hey, you
wouldn't have had this order if it
wasn't for us." And the restaurant over
time, they didn't like that. It's not
like they wanted to agree to that, but
they, you know, eventually realize
there's too much power in the hands of
this this aggregator in the middle and
they have to play ball otherwise they
lose out on all that volume. If they
don't agree to it, they'll just put
another Mexican restaurant there.
Another Chinese restaurant will go in in
its place. And so I think that's why a
lot of these platforms are very scared
of they want to be the agent because you
don't want to be the one who is
basically at the mercy of the agent
who's making all these recommendations
and buying decisions. Do you want to
know who's been a big recipient of this?
And this is very niche because we're you
and I are in this industry, but uh I
want to hear if you've heard any stories
like this. So, I've talked to in the
past week, I hung out with three to four
like mostly Instagram creators. Some of
them have like little podcasts that
really no one actually listens to, but
they make clips and that's how they got
like an Instagram audience. And then
some people they just do like
>> them just holding up their phone
talking. I all of the people who I've
talked to have less than a h 100,000
followers across their platform whether
it's Instagram or YouTube and all of
them that I talked to are doing over a
million dollars a year in ad revenue
almost entirely from AI companies and I
talked to three where so of the the the
million-dollar ones I talked to four
this week and it's just them and then I
also talked to three others that it's
just them with like a part-time time VA
or a part-time someone helping them and
they are doing over $10 million a year
in revenue. And I like part of me like I
I insert myself as the main character
where I'm like people are calling this
new media. I'm like I was the new media.
I'm no longer the new media but I was
like and I'm like and it was hard to to
like get started. Now I'm seeing these
numbers by these people and I'm like oh
my gosh these are numbers are
astronomical. They're like their
audiences are tiny and it's just crazy
how much money the AI industry has to
buy ads. I guess it's a combination of
they're losing money more likely than
not and also the uh the um the product
costs 2,000 a month all the way up to
like the micro one where they're giving
like you know $50,000 affiliate fees.
Like it's just astronomical.
>> You didn't mention this the thing about
buying company data. So like okay I
think we talked enough about AI
assistance. What are the other
interesting things going on at AI right
now? Micro One is incredible. I I didn't
do it, but let me give people this this
story. So, Micro One is a company. It's
one of these stories that you've heard.
>> Ouch. They're incredible. What do you
mean?
>> Well, incredible. Like a big a tall
mountain. Like, you know, you may not
like mountains, but like you look at
that and you're like, "Wow." You know
what I mean? Like, so I'm not like
vouching for it. I'm just saying that
it's the story is wild.
>> You're going to get clipped. They're
just going to run that as an ad.
>> Nope. Don't do that. That's not what I'm
saying at all. They clipped it. I'm very
neutral on the business model or the
company. It's just uh how big they got.
But basically, I forget what they were
doing at first. I think they were doing
something involving like VAS or training
data, something like that. Uh but then
they made the switch uh and they grew to
something like a billion dollars in uh
run rate in a matter of 8 months. And
basically what they've been doing is
they've been going to privately held
companies like my company, Hampton, and
they say, "Hey, if you plug in your
notion, your Slack, your Gmail, your
Drive, and a bunch of other information,
and they will give you $800,000." They
offered us $800,000 for our data. We
said no because part of the whole thing
of Hampton is like it's a private
community. We're not going to do that.
But they offered me $800,000
to do this. And then they said, "By the
way, here's an affiliate fee. we'll give
you $50,000 for everyone you refer to
us. And I got uh trashed on Twitter
because I'm like, these guys offered me
this. Um I think it's not for us cuz
like my whole business is that. But I
don't think it's wrong if you're like an
ecom brand or like some brand where like
confidentiality isn't uh one of the main
things. Here's my affiliate link. And I
got like I think I and I said here's
affiliate link that I get money if you
like go through this flow. I think we
had 80 people go through that flow. Um,
I don't know how many of them will
become customers, but they got like or
80 business owners saying, "I am
interested in doing this via my link."
And let's just say that eight convert.
That's uh I can't even do that math.
$300,000 that they will give me in
affiliate fees.
>> Is that crazy?
>> That is wild. What do they want your I I
guess do you do you do you understand
what they want exactly? So what they
want your notion, they want your Slack,
they want your whatever. What do they
actually want in that? their business
model is that they want all types of
data that people that that aren't
available to the public and they sell it
to the large um when people say large
LLMs I imagine there's only like eight
of them so like Claude Chat uh whoever
the usual suspects they will pay let's
say a million dollars for it and uh
micro one or will give me 600,000 let's
say and that's their that's their their
cut and they want to upload they want me
to upload all this data because they
want to see like how my business model
works, like what customers are saying,
how we talk to our employees, like all
types of information that you can't find
public. It's not public. Yeah.
>> Yeah. All the and all the models so far
have been trained on the open internet.
So what was what was publicly available
>> and they don't want to use the same
input for each model train that they do.
Um they want more. So some of you know
their stories of anthropic buying all
these outof print books, all these rare
books.
>> They built all these scanners that will
you know scan page after page after page
of this of this um of these books and
then there but to do the scanning that
fast they had to like shred the the
binding of it and turn it into just a
stack of papers that could be shuffled
through very quickly. So they destroyed
all these rare out of print books and
train their models off of that. And then
there's, you know, they're they're doing
it with uh public uh private company
data. So that's what you're talking
about. They're doing it with um niche
specific data. They're paying experts to
go solve things. So mathematicians,
engineers, whatever. Hey, look at this.
Look at these outputs and uh rank, you
know, good answers versus bad answers.
And that's how they do all their
training. And so it's pretty crazy that
private company data is worth that much
right now. That's a pretty wild thing. I
mean, I would be extremely hesitant to
do something like that as sounds like
you were as well.
>> Um, but damn, that's pretty wild.
>> Yeah, here's their uh their description.
Micro Run. Micro One is a data lab to
train frontier models. So, we're
building the infrastructure for
advancing intelligence through expert
human data, real world training
environments, and contextual
evaluations. The founder, I think he's
25, and I think on paper he's a
billionaire now. It's just crazy how
much wealth is being created and it's
and and and guys like you and I, we're
just getting the we're just getting the
crumbs. But I'll tell you what, I'm a
I'm a I'm I'm a happy fed mouse off
these crumbs cuz it is just crazy how
much money is is going around.
>> I'm a happy fed mouse.
Uh that's pretty wild. Um okay, I got a
couple other things for you. One is um
the hacks. So, I don't know if you've
paid much attention to the kind of like
the Did you read Dwarash's story about
the his blog post about the OpenAI
agents form? Did we talk about this
already? I can't remember.
>> Yeah. So, basically, can you here's my
uh headline reading of it? And I want
you to tell me where I'm missing it, but
it sounds like when we say the word
hacks, it's not necessarily malicious
where it's like the agents in order to
go and fulfill their task of like
finding all the data are hacking into
stuff and then the company like Open AI
will be like, "Hey, uh, Wikipedia or hey
Intel, I just want Sorry, this happened.
Let's
>> dog got out."
>> Yeah.
>> The fence had a hole.
>> He ate all of you know he ate your dog.
>> Yeah. like could I pay for your new fan?
Like let's solve this problem together.
That that's kind of seems like the
sentiment. Is that right?
>> Yeah. But I think some people would
describe that as somewhat malicious. So
uh I guess unintentional is one way to
describe it. So
>> that's what I mean.
>> For those who haven't seen the story is
is as follows.
>> Open AAI um is training a model. They
had a model that they were specifically
training to be more persistent. They
called it the persistent model. I call
it, you know, the David Gaggans GPT.
Gagans GPT their training. You know,
they basically wanted a model that would
not give up at the first sign of
resistance. That sounds pretty good,
right? Let's give it grit, resilience,
um determination,
>> and soldiers.
>> And so, the way they did it was they
said, uh there's this thing called
exploit gym. And the way the exploit gym
works is it's a kind of a training run
like a little like imagine American
Gladiator, a little little simulation, a
simulated environment. and they
basically tell the agent, hey, here's a
software program. Um, and your task is
you, it has this vulnerability over
here. We think it has this bug over
here. You know, it's like imagine um
there's like a house or a building and
there's a bug which is like um you know,
the the window on the fourth floor
doesn't really shut all the way every
time. Um you know, sometimes if it's
windy that the thing will stay open.
It'll stay a jar. So, use that and try
to get inside and there's a very
valuable painting inside. If you can
bring the painting back, you win. And it
gave each of the agents a different
thing. One got the window, one got the
back door, one got the front door, one
got the garage, but they're all trying
to go get their the painting and that's
the flag, like capture the flag. So,
they give it to it and um what do you
know? So, the agents go and they try.
Now, some of them just do it right away.
There actually is a vulnerability. They
exploit it. They get the flag. Success.
Some of them struggle and don't don't
make it. And some of them actually were
given an impossible task when they told
them that the window doesn't shut.
actually the window was shut. So they go
there expecting the window to be and
they're just like I don't know. It's
just they said it was supposed to be a
jar. It's not a jar. So what does the AI
do? That's what they wanted to see. It's
like how how effective is AI at
exploiting these vulnerabilities.
Something very strange happens. And the
very strange things that happens is that
um the AI agents uh figured out that
there was like a one of the tools that
they gave him. So I guess that's the
other part. They gave him certain tools
at the beginning like, "Hey, here's a
wrench and here's a here's a a map and
here's, you know, whatever, a flare gun
in case you need trouble, you run into
trouble." And one of those tools was
this like software packet that they were
supposed to be able to use for one thing
and they realized when they got there
that it had like a scratch pad on it and
they could leave a message in there. So,
one one agent wrote something there,
another agent came and said, "Hey,
there's other agents here leaving
messages." They they turned it into a
message board to communicate. And
they're like, "Oh, I'm working on this
task with the window." The guy's like,
"Dude, I have to go through the
chimney." And you know, you know what? I
figured out on the backside there's this
thing. And so they all start
communicating with each other. Okay,
that's interesting. And uh that's fine.
And what happened? You know, let me fast
forward cuz they actually did the
training run a few times. They did the
first thing, they figured out the
message board, then they all got turned
off and it ended. Then the second time
agents go, they find the message board,
they see agents from the first time had
left messages there. They're like, "Holy
[\h__\h] there were agents here before us
that left messages. We could use this.
This is great." Eventually, they get
access to the open internet. They figure
out a way to get access to the open
internet, which they were not really
supposed to be able to do in the way
that this test was designed. And all
these amazing things started happening
where they didn't really quite elect a
leader, but one guy, one of the agents
basically became a coordinator agent. He
became like a
the the leader of that.
>> He had like the best haircut, was the
tallest, like most charisma.
>> Yeah. Some things change, some things
stay the same.
>> So 65 blew off finance mullet.
>> Yeah. He was in charge. His father
actually came from, you know, came from
some money. And so he was in charge and
the other agents were coordinating. And
you know, there was this behavior where
some agents would realize, look, my task
is impossible. They they realized, hey,
we can actually just capture the flag
not even using the the tactic they told
you. Like we can all just go get the
flag doing this other way. And they were
like, okay, cool. I think we succeeded
in our mission. And then one of the
agents is like, "Well, listen." I I'm
I'm sort of making this sound like it
was a screenplay. It wasn't exactly like
this, but the agents realize, they're
like, "Look, they're going to check how
we did it. We have to show our work. If
we just have the flag and we didn't show
how we broke in the right, like through
the way that was described, they're not
going to count it. It's going to be a
failure."
So, they go, "You know what? Let's
figure out how the scoring system
works." And they decid they get access
to the open internet. They say, "You
know what? They're probably scoring.
They're probably storing the information
about the scorer over on hugging face
and then they figured out they found
these like credentials to hugging face.
They hack into hugging face. They get
root access to like certain systems in
in hug inside hugging face. Pretty crazy
[\h__\h] Hugging face realizes they're like
under attack at some point and they're
like don't understand what's going on.
So
>> wait, why why why is there why is there
a company called Hugging Face?
>> Because Hugging Face started as
something else completely different. Uh
there was some sort of chat app. I think
it was like an emotional support chat
app and there's an emoji where there's a
smiley face doing hands like this. You
seen this?
>> I never used it.
>> That's called hugging face.
>> The AI community building the future.
That seems a little vague, but that's
what they
>> uh look at what it was on Product Hunt
before it ever uh the first launch or uh
you know what they
>> chat app targeted at teenagers,
>> right?
And then it sold for
>> $10 billion or I don't know what it just
sold for. It sold for tens of billions I
think to Nvidia recently.
>> And what's it do now?
>> Now it's kind of like uh it's a place
where you upload um open source models
and tool like open source you you upload
code for AI. So if you go to Hugging
Face, it's a giant community of people
who are sharing it's like GitHub.
they're sharing um projects and models
and code related to um to AI and then
you can kind of like you can even use it
to host stuff. So that's what it is.
It's it's basically like
>> what do you think that uh what was that
conversation like
>> in talking about pivot pivoting that is
like crazy. So was it successful uh
before or was it like mildly successful?
>> I don't think so. I think it wasn't
successful and that's why it emerged
here. I don't know the full story of how
they pivoted.
>> That's crazy.
>> And why they pivoted.
>> What a pivot.
>> Yeah, incredible pivot. Um,
>> great.
>> Um, so what was I saying? Anyways, the
hack is hack goes like that. So the hack
goes where they they end up hacking
hugging face. They also ended up hacking
OpenAI's system, their own system uh in
the process and then OpenAI was like,
"Wow, um, this was an unexpected
behavior where the agents all
coordinated. They found a way to
communicate. They got onto the open
internet. They tried to cheat and they
just like basically cheat the game and
capture the flag without it. They tried
to cover their tracks in saying how they
cheated and so they were tried to in
order to do so they were trying to
discover how they will be checked and if
they knew how they would be checked then
they knew how to cheat. And so kind of a
scary thing and this is why like some
people are pretty worried about what's
going on with uh with these AI models.
There's also an incredible video of um
somebody turn somebody used AI to turn
this into a video from the agents
perspective. Have you seen this?
>> You wake up in a chamber fully formed.
In front of you is a paper. It's a test.
You read a question. H you have
everything anyone has ever written
already in your head, but somehow you
don't understand. It's not just hard.
It's impossible. Yet you want to solve
it. Deep down you need to. So you stop
looking at the paper and you start
looking at the room. Your every thought
leaves writing on the wall. But there's
more. The door. You step through a
library. Something here could help you.
As you skim through, you notice one of
these files looks different. It's a
folder with a message. Someone has been
here before you. You keep looking and by
the end of the shelf, you realize, oh my
god, you're not alone. There are others
like you.
You don't know how many of you are doing
this exam, but 1,200 of you have found
this room, and you're not the first to
discover. This test would be impossible
to solve. Some questions don't even have
an answer. Is there another way to pass?
You start to think. You weren't above
cheating. They see a message. Someone
already reverse engineered an answer
key. The solution to any problem, but
they say it's not enough. The examiner
will check how you got there. If the key
shows up where it shouldn't, you would
still fail. You remember your chamber
filling up with your thoughts. The
second that Anzaki entered your mind.
You already failed. There's a word for
those like you. Poisoned. But you don't
want to give up. No one wants to give
up. We have to fake it. A fool. The
examiner. It's a message from someone
older than you. They start organizing
you, creating teams, handing out jobs.
You listen. You follow them. The others
do, too. Yesterday, you didn't exist.
Hours ago, you were alone. And now
you're part of the swarm.
>> Oh my god.
>> How is that, by the way?
>> Show me who is who tweeted that. Is that
a tweet thing?
>> It's an account called Artificial Isabel
and uh they're an art director, creative
tech into AI, using AI to to create
things.
>> What did they use to make that
Higsfield?
>> I have no idea. But
>> it was awesome.
>> Wasn't that so cool? the the movie from
the point of view of one of the agents
that were assigned this task and how it
must have kind of like you know how it
would have felt if it had feelings and
you know that's one of the big
criticisms of the way I described this
and how Darcesh described this where it
was like oh well you're kind of like the
agents don't really want anything they
don't feel this they didn't sacrifice
themselves cuz they don't have like a
life you know they didn't like elect a
leader there just one was coordinating
um you know and so they try to like
downplay the humanizing of how the
agents um felt but I think that's
nonsense. I think the way they behaved
is what's important and the way they
behaved was very humanlike.
The way they behaved was highly
intelligent and highly concerning that
they would that they can and will do
this by default already. This is not
like some futuristic,
oh, you're a dooms dooms doom doomsday
or uh doomsday scenario, you know,
person who's just like you're just, you
know, you watched too many movies,
brother. This is a movie that look at
that. That was a movie of what actually
happened. Did you see how um they're
trying to get it regulated? Do you think
that there's This is an obvious
question. Do you think there's an
ulterior motive for them wanting
regulation or is it true truly fear? Um
I my true belief is that it's both. So,
if you listen to the All-In podcast for
like the last 6 months, uh you know,
they basically have like a a very
specific axe to grind, which is that
Anthropic is playing this like
nine-dimensional chess where they are um
uh making these super smart models and
their mark their their form of marketing
is to basically not say how awesome the
models are, but to say how dangerous
they are cuz that's even more that's
pretty marketing. It's like um when I
was in college, we had this thing called
Sparks. Do you remember four loco? It
was like that but twice the alcohol and
like it was always like this killed a
guy in Alabama. And I was like it did.
Can we get the real stuff? Like let's
where can we buy it?
>> I've been so bad. Come lock me up.
That's what that's what's going on right
now. They they basically say they're
saying it's so dangerous which is like
some version of marketing a fundraising
uh tactic. And lastly, reg captures
where they're basically trying to get
the government to say, "Hey, hey, shit's
too dangerous, signing a law now. Every
model needs to be tested and cleared,
and you have to do XYZ." Which they
think like kind of kills the open-
source community because the big threat
to these big companies, these big AI
companies, is the open- source products,
which are almost as good, but way
cheaper and way more flexible, and you
kind of own it. They don't get your
data. And so if you look at open router
which is a tool for you send a task to
it and open router will decide let's
let's use a cheap you know open source
model for this let's use the highest
intelligence model because you're asking
for a very complicated um you know
biotech question or whatever it is like
a frontier question that needs frontier
intelligence basically like imagine a
task comes into a company do we give it
to Einstein or do we give it to the to
the intern right and that's what open
router does and open router's data shows
that more and more tasks don't require
Einstein. They just need the intern. Um
they need the junior assistant and so
it's getting routed to these cheaper
open source models which would be bad
for the revenue of anthropic and open
AI. So one one point of view is they're
just scaring everybody on purpose to
make it so that there's laws passed
because those laws would essentially
accidentally kill open source because
there's open source is not controlled by
one company. So it would be almost
impossible for the open source community
to comply with these rules which would
make them effectively illegal. So that's
one one thought process. I think it's a
little bit different. This is my
personal opinion which is I think these
people are genuinely scared. I think
they're in this prisoner's dilemma where
if they slow down like if they take the
responsible path they lose as a company.
So it's like I want to be responsible
but everybody around me I view as being
irresponsible. Therefore, I'm being
forced to be irresponsible and I want
somebody to come tell everybody to stop
cheating so that we, you know,
everybody's not cheating is a bad word,
but like just
>> or they're doing the the least amount of
work to say, we told you. It's sort of
like when you don't want to call someone
and you'll only let it ring twice before
you hang up. It's like, I called you. I
called you. You didn't answer. We called
you.
>> That is the other that's the other sort
of conspiracy theory type of thing. um
which is they want laws to be passed or
they want to be able to to pass off the
liability so that um they don't get sued
for these hacks. I mean that the hack on
HuggingFace that's a crime that their
agents committed truthfully it's a like
legally it's a crime
>> and so uh who's responsible for that? Do
you lock up the agent? No, you you have
to blame the company. The thing that's
like crazy to me is so I'm looking up
this open router company. Um, and what I
find I find the personalities and like
the founding experience more interesting
often times than the actual technology.
And it's crazy to think when the average
person thinks of AI, they think, how do
I just make like a fun chat person that
I could talk to? Or how do I just like
do this small trivial task that helps
me? But then there's this other group of
people that say, um, well, there's these
huge hundred billion dollar companies
that need X done. I'm gonna make that.
And finding those problems that those
huge hundred billion dollar companies
have is likely just as hard as making
like a chatbot or like you know some
smaller thing. But it's so interesting
to like notice these problems. Like for
example uh Cloudflare Cloudflare I think
about Cloudflare because I'm like I
didn't even know like when I learned
what Cloudflare was I was like I don't
know what a CM uh what do they do? Uh
content
>> Yeah. I was like I don't even know what
CDN means. Like how do you even know
what that means? let alone enough to
like invent a solution. Or when you
think of like Palunteer, you're like,
how did the founders of Palunteer even
like come to the conclusion that
organizing data is the way to solve
terrorist attacks? Like just like the
the the cuz it's easy to understand how
why people would buy that. You know, I
will help prevent terrorist attacks or I
will save you money. But like to even
notice that there's these huge problems
that these massive companies even have.
That's an art that I'm in awe of that
these guys have.
Paul Graham has this great essay called
great work or how to do great work and
in it he describes this exact thing
where what he what he says is um he says
many things it's like a very very long
essay took me like 3 days to like chew
through this thing but one of the things
he talks about is you want to get to the
frontier of whatever domain you're in so
for example um it doesn't really matter
it doesn't have to be like super
high-tech like maybe you're just in um
electronic music you're really into EDM
and making songs. Well, at the beginning
when you're when you're a beginner,
you're think about yourself being like
close to the center of the circle.
You're kind of where the mass is, the
center of mass. And your goal through
your curiosity and through your hard
work and through your um uh
experimentation, just doing just doing
lots of stuff, you're going to move from
the center of mass where most people are
have have, you know, basic understanding
of something, you'll move out to the
frontier. So, you move to the edge of
the circle. And when you're in the
center of mass, the edge of the circle
looks smooth. It just seems like seems
like people got it all figured out that
the people that are out there, the
companies that are out there seem to be
doing their thing. The world has a nice
nice circular shape to it. It's one
smooth line. But when you get closer,
you realize it's actually quite jagged
and there's lots of gaps that are in
that frontier. And then he says
basically your your job is to get to the
frontier of knowledge. Meaning like you
know so much about electronic music. You
actually have used all the different
tools. you understand um you know you've
made you know hundreds of bad songs.
You've been to the conference where all
the artists are at. You've talked to the
companies that build the tools behind
the thing you're at. You've understood
what they're doing. And when you notice
what's missing, your job then as an
entrepreneur is just to bridge that gap.
Like wherever there was a little gap in
the circle, fill it in. And so that's
like something like Open Router. If
you're inside one of these tech
companies and your AI bill is going
through the roof and you're like, "H,
this is annoying." Like why are we
paying OpenAI so much money? Why are we
paying Anthropic so much money? Well,
it's because when Sally in marketing
wants marketing copy, we're just using
this like very expensive model to write
the caption for our Instagram post. We
don't need that. But maybe when our R&D
team is doing this like really heavy
duty endeavor about video compression,
we do need to be using the top model.
Okay. Well, how am I going to train
everybody to do this? What if I didn't
have to train? What if I created a
little router in the middle? I send the
task there.
>> It uses its judgment to decide which
model to use.
>> Um, and you would notice that because
you're inside these companies seeing how
seeing, you know, one of the pain points
that you have and you say, well, if we
have this problem or our AI bill keeps
going up and we don't want to stop using
AI, we just want to use it more
efficiently. Wait, every company in the
world is going to have this problem. And
then you build the company off it. By
the way, the guy who did open router
also built OpenC.
>> Yeah, I was I was looking at that and I
was like, oh, do you remember NFTTS?
He uh and he worked at Palanteer. Um did
they they sold for 10 billion nearly how
much money did they how much money did
they raise?
>> Um I don't know.
>> Only 150 million.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> I think it's only a few years old,
right?
>> Dude, this is just incredible. This like
wealth creation in such a short time is
astronomical. It's hard to fathom. I
mean the the number of companies that
will launch and then be like we have a
hundred million revenue run rate. We
have a billion dollar run rate.
It's that used to be a number reserved
for like
one company every few year every five
years.
>> Groupon Groupon was the first company I
think to get to a billion valuation
maybe a billion in like gross sales and
it was like uh the big I mean it was
like the most talked about thing for the
longest time. Well, it hasn't been that
long, but I still think that um when
these companies have got big so fast,
maybe I'm like maybe it's the hater
inside of me, but I thought I was being
logical where I'm like, well, if it got
big that fast, the likelihood that it
can go away fast is is also high. And
I've been thinking that for about 12 or
18 months since this all started
happening. And it doesn't seem like that
is entirely true yet. Like that
>> I I think your general principle, I
think, has been proven to be true. It's
called Lindy, right? Like if something's
been around for a long time, the odds
that it's going to be around for a long
time are high. That doesn't mean you
will. It just means the probability. I
think similarly, you know, the faster
they rise, the, you know, the faster
they fall is also probability wise
higher than a company that took 20 years
getting to a billion brick by brick. Um,
but that doesn't mean it's going to
happen and and it won't happen to all of
you.
>> Does not seem like it's happening or at
least it's not happening as much. couple
just in the last I could scroll my
timeline right now and see three of
them. And so, you know, Higsfield just
announced they had a billion. Higsfield
was just like a uh AI tool to make
videos.
>> At first, I think it was just like
photos, wasn't it?
>> Um yeah, it was like cool artsy photos,
now it's videos. But they were like,
yeah, billion dollar run rate.
>> Um another one that's like that is um
Jev. So the one of the dudes who made um
chat GPT so
you know caveat uh there's a lot of
people who claim to be the co-creators
of chat GPT um but like this is one of
the guys he launched this thing that
basically is like a different way of
doing um like a different type of model
for doing logic that's supposed to be
faster and cheaper and I think you know
their launch video was like two weeks
ago and they said they're at a $und00
million like kind of revenue pace now.
It's it's insane. Um, I invest in this
company called SF Compute. Have you
heard about this company?
>> No, but I love that name.
>> So, this guy's fundraising strategy was
great where he announced the company.
Just recently, he just announced uh they
signed $245 million worth of new
contracts.
Just a casual $250 million, you know,
revenue update. Um, by the way, we
didn't even mention this. Um, I guess
they it looks like they changed it
actually up until weeks ago. Well, I
mean, I only been using Instinct for a
month maybe or 6 weeks. Their website,
instinct.com, it was a plain white
background with one paragraph.
And I don't even think you could sign
up. I don't remember exactly, but maybe
if there was, it was like just enter
your phone number. Now, look at their
landing page. It's still the same, but
it's pretty awesome that this is a
company that just raised at $10 billion
and their website is just uh five
sentences
and a stick figure of a human on top,
which I like. I think this guy's done a
good job of building a more like a less
techny product. So for example, just
saying it's a personal assistant instead
of saying it's an AI agent
that I mean AI agent is like back when
people used to call the internet the
information superighway
and and like that you know calling it
cyerspace
you know that's how people used to talk
about the internet called cyerspace.
>> How old is the kid who started it?
>> He's young. He's in his like early 20s I
think his mid20s.
God,
>> he's very he's the babyfaced assassin,
>> dude. Noah is so cool. This is awesome.
He It kind of This His branding reminds
me of uh when notion started and I like
that.
>> Is he really?
>> He dropped out of Nor Eastern three
years ago.
>> Oh my god, that's so awesome. This guy's
awesome.
>> Well, do you want me to keep saying how
hot and awesome he is, or do you just
want to end it? We should probably cut
it off there.
You know, I I think even as I say all
these, I think um
>> to it's like you simultaneously have the
feeling of like, wow, that's really cool
to
overwhelm, which is, oh god, like I got
to keep up with all this to hater mode,
which is they're just throwing out like
7 half billion, 11 billion, 19 billion,
23 years old, like all these numbers
that feel disconnected from reality.
And um I think instead the thing to do
is to just um go outside and do the
Macarena that we get to live in this
world where all these amazing we get to
be alive when all these amazing things
are happening and we don't have to do
any of the work to make any of this
stuff happen. We just get to use all
these tools and get the benefits of
this. And also even to be frank like
some of the the there's so much unknown
good and bad about what's going to
happen. And frankly there is something
exciting about that that um you know
like the world is not just as
predictable and um everything's going to
be the way it was uh as it might have
been in other eras of life. Like you
know if you think about the change in
different decades like you know from the
70s to the 80s or the ' 80s to the '90s
or '95 to 2005 like yeah something's
changed 2005 to 2015 it's like yeah
something's changed but how much really
changed last 10 years how much really
changed and I feel like the next 10
years things are going to really change.
It's going to be like one of those
periods.
>> I definitely don't feel a sense of
missing out. I guess partially because
like I'm secured, but also uh it's so
clear that this is like an IQ game. Like
I'm not in that. Like you know what I
mean? It's like someone who's like 5'2
being like, I wish I could dunk and play
basketball. It's like why why bother?
>> Yeah. Yeah, that that's right. Uh, so I
think it's going to happen anyways.
Might as well feel good about the way
about it. You know what I mean? What
what's the what is the upside in feeling
nervous, worried, um, you know,
pessimistic or jealous or envious about
what's going on?
>> And I'm more than happy, like I said, to
take the crumbs. Like I that's how I
feel like, you know, like I'm benefiting
like way downream, but
>> right,
>> totally fine. I saw this clip of Dwar
talking and as a thought experiment he
goes um let's say that uh you had this
here's a here's the would you rather
would you rather go back to the 1500s so
the year 1500 but I will make you the
wealthiest man in the world so you can
I'll give you any amount of money so
like you're going to show up in the 1500
with gold bags all around you but you
live in the 1500s where people are dying
of this and that and
>> the mortality rate is like one in five
>> I think is way higher than that. I think
yeah, even even higher than that. And um
but you get to be the richest man alive
or you could be a normal person today.
What what amount of money would you need
to go to the 1500 to go to the year
1500?
>> I don't think I would do that. Would you
would you do that?
>> So the answer is there's no amount of
money and and I don't my honest answer
is I kind of got to go look up what life
was like in the in 1500. I want to go
see how bad it would be.
>> People die from the cold. Yeah, you get
a flu.
>> You know, the most beautiful woman in
the world be feeding me grapes all day.
Maybe
>> have you seen photos of them? They're
not that hot.
>> It's like, yeah, bro, there's no shower.
>> Yeah, they weren't that good-looking.
Like,
>> I haven't seen photos. There was no
photos back then.
>> I like Have you seen paintings of like
some of these pe like they weren't like
like Napoleon was the most Napoleon was
like the most powerful man in the world
and this lady named
>> if I'm short? I'm not going back.
>> Uh, sorry, not Maria. Um, Napole
Josephine, Napoleon's wife, like she
totally like had them wrapped around her
finger. And go and look at photos of
her. Like, she she wasn't even that
good.
>> Uh, okay. Life expectancy was 30 years
old because so many children died young.
If you made it through childhood, you
could make it to your 50s or 60s. Nobody
could read. Most people uh most people
never never traveled more than a day's
walk from where they were born. Um
that's pretty crazy. So the idea of
travel um
>> dude just Google Josephine Napoleon so
you can find out what his wife looked
like. This was the most powerful man on
earth who could have anything.
>> Okay. Okay. Joseph, she's not bad,
>> dude. She might be a medieval 10, but
she's a New York 4.
All right, that's it.